DHR&Hakugetsu Sub
翻譯：因果律 モビイ·ディック 大湿 時間軸：KoU 後期：水姬 壓制：沙夏 KoU
キャ～～～～ッ！
Wanko!
わんこ！？
If I heard it coming from inside
the house, it couldn't mean...!
今　家の中から
聞こえたってことは　まさか…
Ask before
coming in!!!
It's something I've been
dreaming of for a long time...
そりゃあ　ずっと夢見てたさ
which is to say,
being turned on by a zombie girl...
その　いわゆる
ゾンビっ娘との萌え…
You're not a zombie? Huh?
ゾンビじゃないって…　あれ？
R-Rea...?
れッ　礼弥
Why...? How come you're here?
何で？　どうしてここに
Well, this is your fantasy world, Furuya.
うふふ　だってここは
降谷君の夢想の世界
This is where your wishes come true.
降谷君の願いが　かなう場所
And so, this is your turn-on situation.
だから　これが
降谷君の萌えシチュエーション
Huh?
My turn-on situation...
俺の萌えシチュエーション
To think...
それが…
...that this would actually come true...
本当に　かなっちまうなんて
Nemurenai yoru ni kiita monogatari ga
What if the story I heard that sleepless night
esoragoto da to shitara
was all just an impossible dream?
Eien wo shiru yori kairaku wo motomete
What if I pursue pleasure, and lament the moment
ima wo kuyande shimau no wa
instead of learning about the eternities
kokoro no fukaku ni sumitsuita kage kara
so that I can escape from the shadows
nigeru tame da to shitara
that dwell deep within my heart?
Sore demo atashi wa atashi wa ai shite irareru nara
But even so, as long as I, as long as I can still keep loving
Hanbun ni wareta taiyou ga asa wo tsurete kite
The sun split in half brings with it the morning
yami ni nareta shinkei wo jiwari shigeki suru
gradually stimulating my nerves, so used to the darkness
Okiwasureta ano ai wa aete sono mama de
I'll dare to leave the love that I'd misplaced as it is
Shinario no kieta monogatari wa
A story whose plot has been erased,
jiyuu ni jiyuu ni kaji wo totte
freely, freely, takes the helm,
motto takaku e maiagatte
soaring ever higher
"It`s Because I... Ran Into You"
おい　また叫び声
みたいなのが　しなかったか？
Hey, did you just hear what sounded like another scream?
Yes. I'm sure it came from Lady Ranko.
はい　あの声はきっと蘭子殿
But Brother went to see
about her, so we needn't worry.
でも　にーが行ったようなので
心配はいらないでしょう
Hmm, all right...
うん　そうか
ハア　ハア
J...
J-Just a second! What is this, Chihiro?!
ちょっとーッ！
どういうことよ　千紘
W-Why is the runaway
Miss Sanka up here in your room, Chihiro?!
何で千紘の部屋に
家出してる散華さんがいるのよ
Uh... well...
ああ　えっと…
And what's worse,
she's gravely hurt, isn't she?!
それにこの子
大ケガしてるじゃないの
And yet you haven't taken her
to the hospital, you just left her here!
なのに　病院にも連れてかないで
こんな所にほったらかして
What on earth are you thinking?!
一体　何考えて…
ああ…
That's it, isn't it? She's... a zombie, huh?
やっぱりそうなんだ　この子
ゾンビなのね
Wanko...
わんこ…
There's a deeper reason for all of this.
これには深～いわけがあってだな
You murderer!
人殺し～ッ！
Geez! You really did... go and
kill someone... for your experiments!
もう　アンタ！
ついに　実験のために
人殺しまでするなんて
Hey, wait, wait!
You're wrong! You're wrong!
待て　待て！
違うって
何が違うのよッ
- Oh? How am I wrong?!
- Just hold on! Hey!
ちょッ　おい！
- Police! Police!
警察！　警察！
話を聞けって
- Just listen to me!
- Police! Police!
- Arrest him! Arrest him!
Answer me! What the hell is going on?!
答えなさい　一体どういうことなの
I'm telling you, she drank
some of the drug by accident!
だから事故で　あいつが薬飲んでて
But forget that, just now,
Rea was acting strange!
それより今は　礼弥の様子が変で
Wait...
…って　ああッ
Ah... Babu...
あー　ばーぶー
W-Wait up, Rea!
Where are you going? Damn...
まッ　待てよ　礼弥
どこ行くんだよ　クソッ
わんこ　風呂場に　爺ちゃん
いるから呼んできてくれ
Wanko! Grandpa is down
in the bathroom! Go get him!
Huh? What for?
ええッ　何で？
いいから
Just do it!
H-Hey, wait!
ちょっと待って
私　あのお爺ちゃん苦手
I-I'm not very good at dealing with Grandpa...
Ah, geez... What the
blue blazes is going on?!
もう　一体全体どうなってんのよ！
Hey! Chihiro!
おーい　千紘～ッ
What was all that shouting earlier?
Is everything all right?
さっきの声は何だ？
大丈夫なのか？
I-It was nothing! Wanko was
just watching a DVD, and got startled.
何でもねえよ
わんこがＤＶＤ見て
怖がってただけだから
What are you doing way up there?
You're ignoring your work.
お前はそんな所で
何をしとるんだ？
掃除ほったらかして
Oh, I just have to do something with Babu.
いや　ちょっと　ばーぶの用事で
ふう　またお前は…
Ugh, there you go again.
Get back here soon.
早く戻れよ
はーい
Right!
あれ？　いねえ
Huh?
She's gone... No, don't tell me...!
あッ　まさか…
Huh?
She's eating the hydrangeas...?
あじさい　食べてる
U-Um... Why is she eating them?
えーと　何でそんなもの食べて…
Huh?
あれ？
礼弥の目
Rea's eyes...
The color of her eyes...
瞳の色が…
Huh? Where am I?
あれ？　私…
あッ　降谷…　君？
Furuya...?
She's regained her senses!
意識も元に戻った
Rea!
礼弥！
ふええッ
キャ～ッ！　私どうして
こんなカッコで外に？
What am I doing outside, wearing just this?!
Oh, wait right there!
ちょっと待ってろ
Put this on!
これ着ろッ
After she ate the hydrangeas,
she came back to her senses.
あじさいを食べたら
正気に戻った
That's it. The poison from
hydrangeas was one of the ingredients
そうか　あの蘇生薬の成分には
used to make that reanimation mixture.
あじさいの毒素が含まれている
And so, she's using the effects
of the drug to sustain herself.
だから　その薬の効果を
持続させようとして
I get it now! Rea, you and Babu
分かったぞ　礼弥もばーぶも
are both taking the
hydrangea's poison internally!
あじさいの毒素を
体内に取り入れてるんだ
ええッ　毒？
Huh? Poison?
うむ
さすがは　わしの孫じゃ
Mm-hmm, that's my grandson for you.
I brought him...
連れてきたよ～
爺ちゃん
Grandpa!
So, Chihiro, you were the one
who gave that reanimation pill to Sada,
やはり貞に
蘇生丸を飲ませて蘇らせたのは
and brought her back to life.
千紘　お前じゃったか
What do you mean, Sada?
Are you talking about Rea?
だから貞って　礼弥のことなのかな
Who could you be confusing her with?
誰と間違えてんだよ
Listen to me.
The reanimation pill is not perfect.
いいか
蘇生丸は完璧ではないのじゃ
If you only give them one
of them, and do nothing else,
一度飲ませただけで
放っておくと
they will gradually lose their
rationality and motor functions,
徐々に理性や
運動能力が失われ
揚げ句の果てには元のむくろに
戻ってしまうんじゃ
and in the end, they will
wind up being just a corpse again.
Whatever, Grandpa,
just get off of me, already!
てゆーか　お爺ちゃん
いい加減　離れてよ～ッ！
What are you talking about,
Otoki? You're my missus!
何を言う　お時
めおとの仲じゃ～ッ
I am not Otoki!
私　お時じゃない～ッ
何やってんだよ
What are you doing?
In order to keep the
flesh of the reanimated healthy...
蘇者の肉体を
健康的に維持させるには
...first, you have to have moderate exercise;
ひとつ！　適度な運動
second, a low-temperature lifestyle;
ふたつ！　低温生活
third, replenish the
hydrangea poison frequently!
みっつ！　こまめな
あじさい毒の補給じゃ
In that case, you could
have written that down in the book.
そんならそうと　あの本に
書いてくれればいいのに
You fool!
ばかもん　そういうことは日々の
蘇者への地道な観察により
That comes from regular,
daily observation of the reanimated,
and is something to
be discovered on one's own!
おのが力で発見していくべきじゃ
What kind of logic is that?!
何だよ　その理屈は
What are they talking about?
何の話？
さあ
Beats me.
So what you're saying is, for now,
as long as we've got hydrangeas,
要するに　とりあえずは
あじさいさえあれば
we can prevent any decomposition?
腐敗も
食い止められるってことか？
Nope.
いんや　さっきから言っておろう
Like I told you before, that drug is not perfect.
あの薬は完璧ではないと
You may be able to delay
the progress of decomposition,
腐敗の進行を
遅らせることはできても
but you cannot stop it.
止めることはできんのじゃ
And because of that, I...
そんなわけで　わしは…
I-I hit him...
あッ　当たっちゃった
G...
じッ　爺ちゃん
Grandpa? Grandpa!
爺ちゃん！
Grand...
爺…
ほえ～ッ！
Grandpa...
爺ちゃん…
ハーハッハッハッ
- Wow, today is a glorious day!
いや　本日は千両日和なり
- Looks like he's back to dotty mode again.
- Wow, today is a glorious day!
またボケモードに
入ってしまったのか
He was having a rare moment of lucidity, too.
珍しく正気状態だったのに
Sorry. I really didn't mean to hit him.
ごめ～ん
ホントに当てるつもりは…
Gramps, come on,
we're going back in the house.
じーじ　ほら家に入るですぞ
Grandpa might have gone senile again...
爺ちゃん　またボケちまったけど
...but he told me some very important things.
でも　色々大切なことは聞けた
Insights, even.
洞察か…
やっぱ　俺自身で礼弥の体を
守る方法を探らないと
Sure enough,
I'm going to have to find a way
to preserve Rea's body myself.
By the way, Chihiro...
ところで千紘
あッ
Who is that girl?
あの子は誰だ？
いや　その　父ちゃん
実は　あの子は…
Oh! Well... Daddy, as it happens, she's...
うん？
あのさ
Listen, I was thinking of talking
to you about this later, but...
あとで
相談しようと思ってたんだけど
That is, thinking wouldn't be
good enough; I was going to tell you...
その…　やっぱ思うだけじゃ
ダメだから言おうと思うんだけど
Are those people members of Furuya's family?
あの方は降谷君のご家族の方
Oh, no! They've found out about me!
いけない
私のことバレちゃったんだ
Am I going to be able to stay here anymore?
もう私　ここにいられないのかな
What's wrong, Chihiro?
どうした？　千紘
Daddy, you see...
父ちゃん　あのさ
I want her...
あいつを…
I want to let Rea live here with us!
礼弥を
ウチに住まわせてやりたいんだ
I want to let Rea live here with us!
礼弥をウチに
住まわせてやりたいんだ
See...
その…　細かい事情は言えないけど
I can't go into all the details,
but she doesn't have anywhere else to go.
あいつ　他に行くとこなくて
それに俺…　俺
Besides, I...
I have to take "responsibility" for her.
あいつの
責任を取る必要があるんだ
ふむ…
S-So Daddy...
だから父ちゃん
ふむ　事情
Hmm... Details...
責任ね…
Responsibility, huh?
何だか珍しいな
This is quite unusual...
you, looking so serious about
something other than zombies.
お前がゾンビ以外のことで
そんなに真剣な目をするなんて
U-Uh... yeah...
これもゾンビごとだけど
This does have to do with zombies, though.
I don't know what's happened,
何があったか知らんが
まあ元来　この紫両寺は
but Shiryoji Temple was
originally intended to be a safe haven.
駆け込み寺としても
使われていたしな
Why not?
いんじゃね？
えッ
ホッ　ホントにいいの？
Y-You really mean it?
Yeah. I have no reason to say no, after all.
ああ　断る理由がないからな
Daddy, thanks!
父ちゃん　サンクス！
Hey, Rea! Come on up here!
おーい　礼弥　上がってこいよ
I got permission
from my daddy, so as of today,
父ちゃんから許可もらったから
今日からは
堂々とウチにいていいぜ
you're allowed to stay here openly!
What, you mean you were
already cohabitating in secret?
何だ　お前　既にこっそりと
同棲させておったのか？
C-Cohabitating?! Don't call it that!
同棲って　そういうんじゃねえよ
Hmm... So that's it.
ふ～ん　そうだったんだ
I'm telling you, it is... not...
だから別にそういう…　って
そっか
Oh...
Is that girl...
あの人って…
She's a bit daunting, huh?
ちょっと手強いな
うん？
こんの～ッ
Huh?
Why, you little womanizer, you!
女ったらしが！
あッ　そうだ
私　家の手伝いの途中だったんだ
Oh, right!
I'm supposed to be helping out at home!
Oh, and my apron is all ruined.
Mom's really gonna let me have it.
いや～　もう
エプロンも破れちゃったし
お母さんに色々叱られそう
I'm gonna borrow this shirt, okay? See you later!
シャツ　借りてっから
じゃ　またね～
Oh, and give Miss Sanka my regards!
あッ　散華さんにもよろしく
礼弥がウチに住むことになり
With Rea now staying at our house,
今日から
日記をつけることにした
I decided to start keeping a diary today.
爺ちゃんの言う「日々の蘇者への
地道な観察」のためだ
This is for the "regular,
daily observation of the reanimated."
"Observation Diary of the Dead"
We'll spend every day together,
毎日を共に過ごし
その経過を書き記す
and I'll write down those experiences.
By doing so, I may
be able to discover some hints
それにより日常のどこかから
to developing a way to sustain
Rea somewhere in our day-to-day life.
礼弥を維持する方法のヒントが
見つかるかもしれない
And based on those hints...
そのヒントをもとに…
U-Um...
あッ　あの…
うん？
I'm sorry about this.
すみませんでした
立て続けに降谷君に
迷惑かけちゃったみたいで
It looks like I've put you out
two nights in a row, now, Furuya.
Nah! As it turns out,
I've learned a little bit more
うんにゃ
まあ結果　ゾンビの特性についても
ちょっとだけ分かったしな
about the characteristics of a real zombie.
U-Um...
あッ　あの…
何だよ
What is it?
Are you sure you don't mind
if I monopolize your room, Furuya?
本当に私が降谷君の部屋を
一人で使っていいんですか？
Don't worry about it.
I'm still in the house where I am.
気にすんなよ
ここも家ん中なんだし
That is...
その…
I wouldn't really mind sharing
the room together with you, Furuya...
私は別に降谷君と一緒のままでも
No, that'd be... That kiss
was a close enough call by itself.
いや　それは
キスでもヤバかったのに
一緒にいたら理性が…
If we were to be together,
I'd lose my mind...
Kiss...?!
What do you mean, kiss?!
何ですか　キスって！？
へッ？
Apparently, Rea doesn't remember
what happened during that time.
どうやら礼弥は　あの時のことを
覚えていないらしい
What do you mean?
What are you talking about?!
何ですか？　何なんですか？
Oh, er, i-it's nothing!
I'm imagining things! My mistake!
いやいや　何でもない
気のせい　勘違い
ええ～ッ　もしかしてさっきの
記憶がおぼろげなときに
Huh? Don't tell me that during
the time my memories are dim,
you kissed me!
私にキスを？
違えよ
No, I didn't! You're the one who... er, I mean...
あれは　そっちから
あッ　いや…
I'm the one? I'm the one
who what?! What did I do?!
そっちって何ですか？
私のことですか？
痛い！
No, I... ow!
"Mero's Room"
I'm telling you, it wasn't like that!
だから　違えって
違うのなら何なんですか？
If it wasn't like that,
then what was it like?!
Just take it easy!
落ち着けって
すごい　ばか力だった
Her strength is incredible.
Like her so-called mental
limiters have been undone.
いわゆる脳のリミッターが
外れた状態になっているらしい
You're sure that nothing happened, right?
ホントに何もなかったんですね？
Yeah.
"Namu Amida Buddha"
"Furuya Mero, Class 4-2"
Brother is becoming a man, huh?
あのにーが青春しておるのう
In order to record any
slight changes to Rea's condition,
礼弥の様子の
ささいな変化を記録するため
動画も残しておくことにした
I've decided to make a video record, as well.
No change to her thighs
and soles of her feet.
太もも　足の裏　異常なし
ばーぶ
ウフフ
No change to her upper arms,
or the nape of her neck.
上腕　首筋　うなじ　異常なし
Furuya, what are you doing?
降谷君　さっきから
何をしているんですか？
うん？　ゾンビの観察記録
Hmm? A zombie observational record.
Huh? Oh, no! I'm too shy for that!
ええッ　イヤだ～
何か恥ずかしいです
No, no! Rea, this is for your own good.
ダメダメ　礼弥のためなんだから
これから毎日　穴という穴
全てをムービーに収めてやるのだ
From now on, every day,
I'm going to capture every
nook and cranny for this movie!
Come on, now, show yourself off! Show me!
ほれほれ　もっとよく見せい
見せい
ひーん
Ultimately, this is just for the observational diary.
あくまでも観察記録である
くわ～ッ！
What's the big idea, putting
green peppers in the miso soup?!
味噌汁の具に
ピーマンとは何事か！
Gramps, that's eggplant.
じーじ　それはナスだ
Huh? It is?
えッ？　そうか
Hey, isn't she going to eat?
おい　あの子はいいのか？
Oh, she said she was too shy,
and that she would eat by herself.
何か照れくさいから
一人で食べるって
I made extra, just for her.
一人分　余計に作ったのだが…
Oh, yeah, that's okay.
You won't need to from now on.
いいよ　次からは　いらない
She says that she doesn't
want to impact the family budget.
家計の負担になりたくないって
言ってるから
She doesn't have to worry
over something as trivial as that.
そんなつまらん遠慮は
しなくていいのに
I'd like you to tell her that
as long as she enjoys my cooking,
料理を喜んでもらえれば
それだけで満足であると
伝えてほしい
that's all the satisfaction I need.
Mm-hmm, I'll tell her.
うん　言っとくよ
色々とやっかいな問題は多い
There are a lot of thorny problems.
Then again, even if she can't taste it,
それとも味は感じなくても
食事のまねくらいは
できるのだろうか？
she can at least go through
the motions of eating, right?
Here. I brought some things
for her personal care, to start with.
はい　とりあえず
身の回りのもの持ってきた
えッ　じゃあ下着とかも？
Like, underwear, and stuff?
I'm not about to lend her my underwear.
さすがに下着は貸せないから
I'll go buy her some tomorrow.
明日　買って持ってくるよ
じゃあね
Bye.
Hey, Wanko...
あッ　わんこ
うん？
礼弥は　そんなんじゃないから
マジで
Rea and I aren't like that. Honest.
Why are you offering excuses?
何　言い訳してんの？
I'm telling you, it's not an excuse!
だから言い訳じゃなくて
分かってるって
Yeah, I know. Bye.
じゃね
あッ　わんこ
Ah, Wanko!
何？
What?!
Thanks, man.
ありがとな
I've now secured clothing
for her for the immediate future.
これで当面の着替えは確保した
But then, since she has no metabolism,
まあ新陳代謝がないのだから
着替えなくてもいいのか
I guess she really doesn't
have to change clothes.
On the other hand,
Rea's feelings are the same as before.
とは言っても　礼弥の気持ちは
前と同じだからな
その様を見て
Looking at them like that,
it makes me feel awfully sad, somehow.
何だかひどく
悲しい気持ちになってしまった
だって　彼らはもう
俺達とは違う存在なわけで
I mean, they're now different
beings than the rest of us.
Furuya!
降谷君
Oh, sorry!
あッ　ごめん
I brought you something to change into.
着替え　持ってきた
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
つまり　もう生きていないわけで＞
In other words, they are no longer alive.
なあ
うん？
Listen...
Is this okay? Just walking?
いいんですか？　散歩なんて
Yeah, it's fine.
構わねえよ
I mean, Grandpa said
you needed moderate exercise.
つうか　爺ちゃんも適度な運動が
必要って言ってたし
All right.
はい
For some reason,
it was an unusual sight.
それは何だか
不思議な光景だった
To them, we probably
look like an ordinary couple.
彼らの目には　多分俺らは
普通のカップルに見えている
でも　こいつはゾンビなんだ
But she is a zombie.
At first, I was astonished,
最初はビックリしたし
and thought I'd fallen into
the greatest turn-on situation,
最高の萌えシチュエーションだと
思ったりもしたけど
but looking at it now, everything
has ended up completely normal.
こうなってみると全部
普通のことになってしまうんだな
Time passes the same
for both people and zombies.
人にも　ゾンビにも
同じ時間が流れてるんだ
Furuya...
降谷君
I don't have to use the bathroom at all anymore.
私　全然トイレに
行きたくならないんです
O-Oh, yeah?
そう
I don't ever get sleepy, either.
全然　眠くもならないの
That's because, of course...
それって　やっぱり…
I feel like, I really have died, huh?
私　ホントに
死んじゃったんだなって
Mm-hmm.
But for some reason,
I feel extremely happy.
でも　何だかとっても
幸せな感じがするんです
もし普通に死んじゃってたら
If I had died in a normal way...
Well, I don't know if there's an afterlife,
あの世なんて
あるかどうかも分からないし
and I don't know if
we become ghosts, or anything.
幽霊にだってなれるかどうか
分からないし
And even if we do, I might
not be able to go for a normal walk,
なれても
こうして普通にお散歩したり
or be able to talk to you like this, Furuya.
降谷君とお話ししたり
できないかもしれない
I might be cut out to be a zombie.
私　ゾンビ向いてたかもしれません
降谷君　ありがとう
Furuya, thank you.
It's because I ran into you
あなたに会えたから
私もこうして自由になれました
that I have become as free
as I am... zombie notwithstanding.
ゾンビだけど
But as it stands, you are
going to start decomposing sometime...
でも　お前はこのままだと
いつか腐敗してしまって
...and before too long...
そして　やがては…
I'm going to keep, you know...
これからも　その…
"taking responsibility for you"
from here on, as well.
ちゃんとお前の責任取りは
しっかりしてやるからよ
Then...
じゃあ…
これからの私の体
大切に扱ってくださいね
Please continue to treat
my body with care, okay, Furuya?
降谷君
You know, when you say it like that...
お前　その言い方って…
Huh? Did I say something funny?
ええ～　何か変ですか？
Yeah, that sounded funny!
変だよ　変
Now come on, let's go.
てか　もう行くぞ
はい
Right!
Is there really a way to completely
stop her from decomposing?
腐敗を完全に食い止められる
方法なんてあるんだろうか？
A way to go on sustaining Rea,
while her wishes are granted?
礼弥の望みをかなえながら
維持し続ける方法なんて
And what happens when the
hydrangeas go out of season?
更に　あじさいの季節まで
終わってしまったら…
If I can just find some other way...
何かもっと
他の方法が見つかれば
If I can just find something...
見つけることができれば
Watch out!
危ない！
危なかった
That was close.
Are you all right, Furuya...
大丈夫でしたか？　降谷…
Furuya! I'm so sorry! I...
What do I do?
降谷君！　ごめんなさい
私…　どうしよう
I-I'm fine.
大丈夫だって
脳のリミッターは
外れっぱなしらしい
It looks like her mental
limiters are still undone.
はあ　でも…
But...
大変！
Oh, no!
H-Hey, it's all right! I'm fine!
おい　いいって　平気だから
Doing this will disinfect it.
こうすると殺菌になるんですよ
Hitotsu dake kanau no nara
If I had just one wish
kimi no te no naka yureru chiisa na hana de itai
I would want to be a small flower, trembling in your hands
Hajimete miru mabushii kono sekai ga
Even if I become separated from you,
kimi to moshi hagureta to shite mo kitto
in this bright world I'm seeing for the first time,
mitsukedashite
I'm sure I'll find you
Mezametara soba ni iru yo
When I wake up, I'll stay beside you
ashita mo
tomorrow as well
Preview
尺に　おさまるように？
Keep it measured? Yeah, I know.
分かっておるわ
慣れなくてすまんな
Sorry it's taking so long to get settled in.
I'll roll it all in in one
take today. It's all right, relax.
今日は巻きでいくからな
大丈夫だ　安心せい
"Childhood... Friends..."
Next time on Sankarea, episode 7: "Childhood... Friends..."
Do you all know the movie director,
降谷千紘の
名前のもとになった
who is famous for zombies, that Furuya Chihiro's name is based on?
ゾンビで有名な
映画監督が分かるかな？
正解はみんな
フルチで調べてみるメロ！
The answer is Fulci! Check it out mero!
Huh? T-Too much left over? Eh...? Eh...?
あ　余った　えッ？